Guide to the Laura Dean Papers, 1966-2007
American Dance Festival Archives Durham, N.C., USA
- Video, 1973-2001, 7 Boxes
  - Ballets and Other Companies, 1985-1999
    - Earth, Laura Dean, Ohio Ballet, EJ Thomas Hall, Akron, OH, Feb. 12, 1993
    - Earth, Laura Dean, Ohio Ballet, Joyce Theatre, Feb. 26, 1995
    - Earth, Laura Dean, Ohio Ballet, commissioned by Richard Kosinski and John Zeretzke (3 copies)
    - Delta, Laura Dean, Royal Danish Ballet, 1990
    - Delta, Laura Dean, Dec. 20, 1990 (PAL format)
    - Cloud, Laura Dean, Royal Danish Ballet, 1994
    - Cloud, Laura Dean, Royal Danish Ballet, 1994 (PAL format)
    - Force Field, Laura Dean, Steve Reich, Joffrey Ballet Performance, Iowa City, Feb. 26, 1986 (2 copies)
    - Sometimes it Snows in April, Billboards, Joffrey Ballet, Apr. 11, 1993
    - Sometimes it Snows in April, Billboards, Joffrey Ballet, Hancher Auditorium, Jan. 28, 1993
    - Sometimes it Snows in April, Billboards, Joffrey Ballet, 1993
    - Creative Force, Laura Dean, Joffrey Ballet, Auditorium Theatre, Oct. 1999
    - Arrow of Time, Laura Dean, Berkshire Ballet, 1989
    - Night Wind, A.I.C., Oct. 1, 1993; Night Wind, Mahaiwe Theatre, Oct. 14, 1993
    - Ni Bthaska Ke, Laura Dean, Ballet Omaha, Orpheum Theatre, Apr. 28, 1995
    - Earth, Laura Dean, Atlanta Ballet, Feb. 20, 1999
    - Tehillum, Laura Dean, Bat Dor Dance Company of Israel, 1984
    - Dream Collector, Laura Dean, Concert Dance Company of Boston, Northeastern University, Boston, Feb. 5, 1988 (Box 21)
    - Burn, Laura Dean, John Curry Skaters, Royal Albert Hall, 1983
    - Ocean, Laura Dean, The Next Ice Age, 1989
    - New Dance, Cherokee NC, Rehearsal, 1998
  - Works Created for Students, 1974-2001
    - Line and Circle, Student Workshop, Pratt Institute, Tapes 1 and 2, Oct., 1974 (2 tapes) (Box 21)
    - Songdance, American U. Student Workshop, Washington, D.C., Aug. 12, 1976
    - Line and Circle, Laura Dean Choreography and Music, Laura Dean and Pat Graf each playing piano live, Putney Vermont Student Workshop, Windham College, June 27, 1977
    - Oberlin Pieces, Laura Dean Music and Choreography, Oberlin Student Workshop, Jan., 1979
    - Music and Dance, Laura Dean, Jason Cirker, California State, Humboldt, 1988
    - Dance for Eight Women, Columbia College, SC, 1993
    - Breath of Fire, Cal State University, Long Beach, 1995
    - Sea, Laura Dean, Loyola Marymount University, Los Angeles, CA, Apr. 5-6, 1995
    - Ultimate Journey, University of Utah, Department of Dance, PDC, Apr., 2001
- Additions to Video
  - Light Field, Joffrey Ballet, Kennedy Center, June 4, 1993 (2 copies) (Box 21)
  - Night, Joffrey Ballet, Iowa City, May 8, 1982, NTSC DVD
  - Night rehearsal, Joffrey Ballet, Studio run with music, Oct. 18, 1980, 3 groups of solos, Studio run with metronome, Oct. 3, 1980
- Audio, 1980, 1 audiocassette
  Access to the original audiocassette in this collection is restricted. Any use of audio requires the use of reference copies. To arrange for the creation of reference copies, if none exist, please contact American Dance Festival Archives.
  - Tympani, Laura Dean, 1980 (Box 21)